

#### Contact:

Mail vibinsahdevm@gmail.com
Mobile +919846274356

Address: Muthalangil House, Amarakkuni. P. O, Pulpally, Wayanad Dist. Kerala, India - 673579

#### **Personal Profile:**

DOB 13/08/1989

Nationality Indian

Marital Status Single

# Languages Known:

English, Hindi, Malayalam & Tamil

# VIBIN M S

GIS expert, specialized in aviation industry, looking forward to work for a progressive organization in a highly motivating and challenging environment that provides the best opportunities to grow and utilize my potential to the fullest to achieve the organization's goal while achieving my personal goal.

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## Sr. GIS Analyst

Jan 2018 to Present

# Airports Authority of India

# **Achievement/Tasks**

- Aeronautical Charts preparation as per ICAO (International Civil Aviation Organization) standards.
- eTOD (Electronic Terrain and Obstacle Data) project lead.
- Feasibility study for India's first Seaplane operation Statue of Unity and Sabarmati Riverfront Water Aerodromes.
- OLS (Obstacle Limitation Surface) survey of different Airports in India.
- Verification and Validation of Water Aerodrome data and charts.
- Feasibility study of Greenfield Airports in India.
- Verification and validation of CNS (Communication and Navigation Systems) facilities.
- Validation of NOC cases.

#### **GIS Executive**

Nov 2015 to Dec 2017

# Gosoft e Solutions Pvt. Ltd., Chennai.

#### **Achievement/Tasks**

- OLS (Obstacle Limitation Surface) survey of different Airports in India.
- Aeronautical Charts preparation as per ICAO (International Civil Aviation Organization) standards.
- Feasibility study of Greenfield Airports in India.
- Survey of new construction sites for NOC purposes.

# **EDUCATION**

#### **Masters in Geoinformatics**

Gandhigram Rural Institute, Tamilnadu, India

2015

## **Bachlors of science in Electronics**

Kannur University, Kerala, India

2012

#### DISSERTATION

Final semester project on "Classification and Vectorization of Powerline in 3D using LiDAR Techniques" from December 2014 to March 2015, from Sky Group - GIS Consultants and Services, Bangalore.  Case Study on "Inventory of Medicinal and Aromatic Plants in Sirumalai Hills, Tamil Nadu using Remote Sensing and GIS Technology"

# **SOFTWARES KNOWN**

GIS : ArcGIS, QGIS, GPS Map Edit, etc

CAD : AutoCAD Map 3D

DIP : ERDAS Imagine, Global Mapper, etc.

LIDAR : Microstation V8

**PROCESSING S/W**: TBC, Leica Geo Office, etc

## **SKILLS/INTERESTS**

- Digital Catrography
- Digital Image Processing
- Remote sensing
- LiDAR
- Field Survey

# **EQUIPMENT HANDLING**

- DGPS
- Total Station
- Handheld GPS

#### CERTIFICATES/APPRECIATION

- Appreciation Certificate from Executive Director, Airports Authority of India for publishing eTOD data of airports for India.
- NCC C certificate with B Grade.
- NCC B certificate with B Grade.
- Attended NCC National Integration Camp in Gaziabad, Uther Pradesh

# **HOBBIES**

- Singing Part of music bands.
- Reading Books.
- Travelling.

# STRENGTH

- Self-motivated.
- Skilled at learning new concepts quickly, working well under pressure, and communicating ideas clearly and effectively.
- Optimistic, Team spirited, and result focused.
- Work within any situations to enrich creative and personal skills.

#### **DECLARATION**

I **VIBIN MS**, hereby declare that the above statements made by me in this application and the documents proceeded in support there are true to the best of my knowledge and belief.

Place:

Date: VIBIN MS